<archimate:Folder
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Organizational, Business and Product Viewpoint (B)"
    id="a608b00e-9f4f-4cd4-b3cb-f949df846862"
    documentation="C.1.1  Organization Viewpoint&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The organization viewpoint focuses on the (internal) organization of a company, department, network of companies, or of another organizational entity. It is possible to present models in this viewpoint as nested block diagrams, but also in a more traditional way, such as organizational charts. The organization viewpoint is very useful in identifying competencies, authority, and responsibilities in an organization.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Table 13: Organization Viewpoint Description&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Organization Viewpoint&#xD;&#xA;Stakeholders&#xD;&#xA;Enterprise, process and domain architects, managers, employees, shareholders&#xD;&#xA;Concerns&#xD;&#xA;Identification of competencies, authority, and responsibilities&#xD;&#xA;Purpose&#xD;&#xA;Designing, deciding, informing&#xD;&#xA;Scope&#xD;&#xA;Single layer/Single aspect&#xD;&#xA;Elements&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;•  Business actor&#xD;&#xA;•  Business role&#xD;&#xA;•  Business collaboration&#xD;&#xA;•  Location&#xD;&#xA;•  Business interface&#xD;&#xA;C.1.2  Business Process Cooperation Viewpoint&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The business process cooperation viewpoint is used to show the relationships of one or more business processes with each other and/or with their environment. It can be used both to create a high-level design of business processes within their context and to provide an operational manager responsible for one or more such processes with insight into their dependencies. Important aspects of business process cooperation are:&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;•  Causal relationships between the main business processes of the enterprise&#xD;&#xA;•  Mapping of business processes onto business functions&#xD;&#xA;•  Realization of services by business processes&#xD;&#xA;•  Use of shared data&#xD;&#xA;Each of these can be regarded as a “sub-viewpoint” of the business process cooperation viewpoint.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Table 14: Business Process Cooperation Viewpoint Description&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Business Process Cooperation Viewpoint&#xD;&#xA;Stakeholders&#xD;&#xA;Process and domain architects, operational managers&#xD;&#xA;Concerns&#xD;&#xA;Dependencies between business processes, consistency and completeness, responsibilities&#xD;&#xA;Purpose&#xD;&#xA;Designing, deciding&#xD;&#xA;Scope&#xD;&#xA;Multiple layer/Multiple aspect&#xD;&#xA;Elements&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;•  Business actor&#xD;&#xA;•  Business role&#xD;&#xA;•  Business collaboration&#xD;&#xA;•  Location&#xD;&#xA;•  Business interface&#xD;&#xA;•  Business process/function/interaction&#xD;&#xA;•  Business event&#xD;&#xA;•  Business service&#xD;&#xA;•  Business object&#xD;&#xA;•  Representation&#xD;&#xA;•  Application component/collaboration&#xD;&#xA;•  Application interface&#xD;&#xA;•  Application process/function/interaction&#xD;&#xA;•  Application event&#xD;&#xA;•  Application service&#xD;&#xA;•  Data object&#xD;&#xA;C.1.3  Product Viewpoint&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;The product viewpoint depicts the value that these products offer to the customers or other external parties involved and shows the composition of one or more products in terms of the constituting (business, application, or technology) services, and the associated contract(s) or other agreements. It may also be used to show the interfaces (channels) through which this product is offered, and the events associated with the product. A product viewpoint is typically used in product development to design a product by composing existing services or by identifying which new services have to be created for this product, given the value a customer expects from it. It may then serve as input for business process architects and others that need to design the processes and ICT realizing these products.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Table 15: Product Viewpoint Description&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;Product Viewpoint&#xD;&#xA;Stakeholders&#xD;&#xA;Product developers, product managers, process and domain architects&#xD;&#xA;Concerns&#xD;&#xA;Product development, value offered by the products of the enterprise&#xD;&#xA;Purpose&#xD;&#xA;Designing, deciding&#xD;&#xA;Scope&#xD;&#xA;Multiple layer/Multiple aspect&#xD;&#xA;Elements&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;•  Business actor&#xD;&#xA;•  Business role&#xD;&#xA;•  Business collaboration&#xD;&#xA;•  Business interface&#xD;&#xA;•  Business process/function/interaction&#xD;&#xA;•  Business event&#xD;&#xA;•  Business service&#xD;&#xA;•  Business object&#xD;&#xA;•  Product&#xD;&#xA;•  Contract&#xD;&#xA;•  Application component/collaboration&#xD;&#xA;•  Application interface&#xD;&#xA;•  Application process/function/interaction&#xD;&#xA;•  Application event&#xD;&#xA;•  Application service&#xD;&#xA;•  Data object&#xD;&#xA;•  Technology service&#xD;&#xA;•  Artifact&#xD;&#xA;•  Material&#xD;&#xA;•  Value"/>
